Welcome to Learning How to Learn.
Your brain has amazing abilities,
but it didn't come with an instruction manual.
Perhaps the greatest gift that our brains give us
is the ability to learn new things every day.
On my way here, I thought about the journey that will take
us to the last day of the course,
and how much we will learn along the way.
Our goal is to give you a better understanding of how we
learn so that your brain becomes a better learner.
These insights are based on solid research from neuroscience,
from cognitive psychology,
and also from dozens of leading instructors
and practitioners in difficult to learn subjects.
Whether you're a novice or an expert,
you will find great new ways to improve your skills
and techniques for learning,
especially related to math and science.
This course is meant to help you reframe
how you think about learning,
to help reduce your frustration
and increase your understanding.
We approach things a little differently.
You're not expected to have an in-depth background
in any particular subject.
Instead, you're expected to take these ideas
and apply them to whatever subject
you're trying to learn or improve in
to help you learn more deeply, effectively,
and with less frustration.
You'll hear experts from a variety of different disciplines
talking about their best tips for learning more effectively.
You can benefit from these ideas
whether you are struggling in high school
or soaring through math and science
at graduate levels at a university.
I'm a co-director of a science and learning center
that is sponsored by the National Science Foundation
based here in La Jolla.
In recent years, we've made great strides from research
in discovering how to learn most effectively.
Finding a way to simply and effectively
share these ideas with you has been a big undertaking,
but we feel it's well worth doing.
You'll see that many of these ideas,
although simple, are incredibly powerful.
And along the way, we will also learn a lot
in the process of teaching you.
You'll see how you can fool yourself
about whether you actually know the material.
You'll discover new ways to hold your focus
and embed the material more deeply
and powerfully in your mind.
And you'll learn to condense key ideas
you're learning about so you can grasp them more easily.
Master the simple, practical approaches outlined here,
including simple tips to help prevent procrastination,
and you'll be able to learn more effectively
and with less frustration.
This course is meant to enrich
both your learning and your life.
You'll be able to get what you want from this material.
So welcome to the course.
And happy learning.